Joshua Wilson

Versatile software developer with 5+ years of experience working with teams and building applications with especially deep knowledge of building tools and services in Python for the financial services and scientific communities. @wilsojb is my handle on many services.

Brooklyn, NY (919) 323-6369 wilsojb@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/wilsojb wilsojb.io

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Developer, TripExpert, NYC

NOV 2015 - PRESENT

I am developing an app for iOS and Android built using Cordova, AngularJS, and the Ionic framework that complements tripexpert.com.

Operations Engineer, Hudson River Trading, NYC

APRIL 2011 - SEPT 2015

Was a member of a tight-knit team responsible for monitoring market conditions, connectivity, and all continuously deployed internal systems. Working on a new feature, debugging legacy software, reviewing a pile of pull requests, and dealing with a market outage were all in a day's work. I also played an active role in their hiring, training, and documentation efforts.

I spent most of my time developing internal tools in Python, Perl, and Bash and played an integral role in converting a legacy code base into a library of tools used company-wide. Part of that involved meeting with other engineers and business teams on a regular basis to discuss requirements, but mostly it meant banging out high-quality work as fast as possible. I helped define and steward technical standards and implemented a test-driven development lifecycle. I was also responsible for administering and scaling a MongoDB replica set.

Research Assistant, University of North Carolina, NC

DEC 2008 - DEC 2010

Physics student finds a home in the Department of Physical Oceanography and studied numerical fluid dynamics there for a few years. In addition to completing **Numerical Approximations to the Boussinesq Equations** (http://bit.ly/1OGfzIn) and publishing the source code I used to write it (see pdelab), I also got to live on a ship for two weeks in the Massachusetts Bay in order to collect data. It was awesome.

LANGUAGES (+ dbs + fwks)

Fluent in Python, Perl, Bash, MongoDB, and Unix/Linux.

Working knowledge of AngularJS, Ionic, HTML/CSS, Node, Redis, Cordova, MySQL, Git/SVN, SciPy, PyQt, TCP/IP, and FIX.

I'm also familiar with C++, jQuery, Go, Ruby on Rails, PHP, Paraview, and Java.

%E atom, sublime, emacs, Sketch, and :q in vi

A LITTLE EXTRA

Backpacking is my favorite mode of transportation. I've done it through Europe, India, and Southeast Asia (so far). I love snowboarding and hiking and really anything outdoors. I'm a to-do list geek, a crontab nerd, and enjoy cooking big, elaborate meals for my friends and family. I'm always in the middle of 2-3 books and enjoy fixing the 1999 Jeep Cherokee that I share with my girlfriend.

My complete work history can be found at linkedin.com/in/wilsojb

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC

M.S. in Physics, December 2010

My emphasis was in numerical modeling and culminated with the publication of **Numerical Approximations to the Boussinesq Equations** (http://bit.ly/10GfzIn)

Hendrix College, Conway, AR

B.A in Physics w/ minor in Computer Science, May 2008

I presented twice at the American Physical Society's annual conference. Here a the links to the abstracts: Laser Assisted Cancer Immunotherapy: Surface Irradiation (http://bit.ly/1kmwHWZ) and Construction and Calibration of a Six Degree of Freedom Thrust Sensor (http://bit.ly/1RlYpo4).

OPEN SOURCE

Snapsite

http://github.com/wilsojb/snapsite

Simple (temporary) website deployment from the command line. An experiment that used Flask, Google App Engine, and Datastore.

Pdelab

http://github.com/wilsojb/pdelab

An object oriented framework for solving and analyzing PDEs. Homegrown solvers, graphing utilities, and examples that came out of grad school.